Hello Hi Friends Welcome back to our channel
Nishan Now we take health insurance
so that our maximum plan or any
medical emergency expenses are covered
and it is applicable for you and your entire
family Friends Therefore, it is very important
that before choosing your health insurance, you
understand what benefits your health insurance
provides and which
plan is best for you. Therefore, in this video
we have brought for you a
full review of Star Health Comprehensive Plan so that you
can choose for yourself whether you should take this plan
or not Friends Here I would
like to tell you that neither I am an agent nor
I get commission from any company. The
purpose of making my video is that you
can choose the best plan for yourself
Friends Before moving ahead,
you must subscribe to our channel Friends and
enjoy the clock that you see on the screen so that you get my latest
videos first Friends
Before understanding the details of the plan, I would like to tell you something
about Bihar Health Insurance
IRDA which is India's
insurance related agency.  The regulatory body has
its Anwar Report 2019 which
was published in December 2018. According to that,
in 2019, Star Health Insurance issued
policies like Shraddha Health Insurance,
which is the highest number of policies for any standalone health
insurance company.
Friends, let's take the INR of Star Health
Insurance which is 63.22%.
This should be the rate for any good health insurance company.
From INR, we get to know
how much percentage of the premium collected by the company is
returned to the policy holders.
Friends, let's move ahead without any delay
and understand the details of the policy.
In this video, we have reviewed Star
Health's Star Comprehensive Plan which is
available for both individuals and families. So, let's now take the first feature of the policy, the
sum insured. It tells us
what will be the maximum limit at the time of withdrawal. There is a
minimum policy in any policy.  5
lakh and the maximum plan is of one crore.
Friends, you can
add a maximum of two elders and three dependent children in any one line. The
minimum age of dependent children should be
3 years and the maximum age
of dependent children can be one, i.e. 25
years. Friends, if you are taking a policy for the first time,
your maximum age can be
65 years and there is
no maximum age for renewing the policy, that is, if
you have taken a policy, then you
can renew it for life. Friends, let's talk about
these hospitalization expenses. If
your hospitalization is for more than 24 hours,
then all your medical expenses will be
covered in this. Included in this is room
rent. Single
private AC room is covered in Star Comprehensive. The next
component is the fees of surgeon,
vested medical practitioner, consultant and place of residence.
Friends, all the expenses covered in the policy are
blood oxygen, operation
theatre charges,
diagnostic X-ray, chemotherapy, dialysis,
medicine charges etc. Friends,
next  The feature is pre-hospitalization
expenses, that is, if your
hospitalization is for more than 24 hours, then the
expenses before that will also be covered. The
limit here is 6 days and it includes charges like
medicines, consultation
fees, diagnostic related charges etc.
Similarly, post-hospitalization charges are
discovered till 90 days after discharge.
Friends, the next feature is curative bonus.
If you do not make any claim in the policy year, then
when you go for renewal next year,
an
amount will be added to your sum without any additional
premium. If your policy is of Rs 5 lakh,
then this amount will be 50%
and the maximum can be up to 100%.
If you do not make any claim for two years,
and if your policy
is of more than Rs 1.5 lakh, then if you do not renew it in a year, then
your sum insured will double in the next year without any
additional premium. Let us understand this with an example.
Suppose Ram has a policy of Rs 10 lakh
and he did not make any claim in the first year.  If you do not make a claim, then the
sum insured will automatically
increase by 100% i.e. 10 lakhs next year. The
basic review here remains the
same. Friends, the
thing to note here is that whenever you plan,
your additional curative bonus will
fall at the same rate at which it increased. That is, if
Honorable Ram makes a claim in the second year, then
when he renews it in the third year,
his sum insured will become
10 lakhs, which is equal to the original sum insured.
Hello friends, now let's move to the
restore benefit. If
during your claim, both the basic sum insured plus curative bonus get combined, then for the
next
day the company
automatically recharges 100% of the basic sum
insured in your account. Let us
understand this with an example. Suppose Ram has a
fabric policy and he does
not have any humanity bonus yet and his first
claim is of 6 lakhs, then his first claim will be of
25 lakhs.  He will pass but his
basic sum insured of Rs 5 lakh will be recharged again for the next day for
that policy year.
He does
not need to pay any additional premium for this. Friends, the
restore benefit in Star Comprehensive can
also be used for health related illnesses
and its benefit will be available once in a policy year, that is,
maximum
100% of the basic sum insured can
hardly be recharged. Friends, the
next feature is road ambulance
expenses. Whenever you are hospitalized,
you can claim the ambulance charges
and you will get an additional refund on this. You
can claim this charge whenever
you are going to be hospitalized by ambulance
or are going from one hospital to another
or are
coming back home after hospitalization.
Friends, the next feature is organ donor
expenses. In this policy, if you are getting a
transplant done, then the
hospitalization expenses of the donor are also covered,
but the important thing here is that only the
hospitalization charges are covered.  Donor
's free hospitalization, opposite
hospitalization charges will not be covered and
whatever expenses will be incurred will
not be covered in your basic plan. This is a very
good feature friends. The next feature is
treatment, that is, those medical
procedures in which the hospitalization is
less than 24 hours.
All the
statements are covered in comprehensive. Some examples of this are
tonsillitis, cataract, radiotherapy or
chemotherapy etc. Friends, the
thing to be noted here is that the treatment should
not be done in the outpatient department
and you can see the list of all the day care procedures
in the policy document.
Friends, the next feature is domiciliary
hospitalization, that is, hospitalization at
home. This is applicable when you
need hospitalization but you are
not able to get hospitalized and the
reasons for this could be that the patient's condition is such
that he cannot be shifted to the hospital
or there is no room available in the hospital.
Friends,
in hospitalization at home, the treatment
must be done under a registered medical practitioner
and also  Pre and post
hospitalization expenses will not be covered here
Friends, the next feature is maternity
cover because this is a very unique feature of this policy.
Normal and section
are covered here and its limit depends on
how much is your sum insured Friends,
here the expenses incurred on the newborn baby are
also covered up to a limit and
its limit depends on your sum
insured Also, friends,
vaccination charges of the newborn baby
are also covered up to a limit Friends, the
important thing to note here is that both the
parents should be covered for a minimum of Rs.1000 in the policy only
then you
can avail the benefit of this feature Friends, this feature
is OPD charges which is
a unique feature of Star [ __ ] Principle Here
your OPD expenses can be refunded up to a certain limit
which depends
on your sum insured and the maximum
consultation refund amount is ₹3000 Friends, the
next feature is OPD  Charges for dental
and after treatment options i.e. IIT,
if you continue the policy for three years, then
your limit is Rs.
202, then it will depend on your per capita coverage.
Friends, the next feature is AYUSH i.e.
Ayurveda, Unani, Yoga,
etc. This
is also covered up to a limit in Star Comprehensive. Friends, the next
feature is health checkup, you get it
in every Clean Premier. Friends, the next benefit
is hospital cash benefit. When you are
hospitalized, you will get cash per day
and its mode depends.
For a policy of Rs. 10 lakh on Swami Shot, the
amount is Rs. 700 per day and the maximum will be available only
till you continue in the hospitalization
and the maximum will be available only for hospitalization up to 120 days in a year.
Friends, the next feature is Values
Program. Here, if you do some divine
activities like walking, cycling,
running or get timely preventive health
checkup done, then when you renew it,
you can get a discount of up to 20 percent.
Hello friends, the benefit is accidental death
and permanent total disability. If you
die due to any reason or if you become
permanently disabled during an accident,
then you will get 100% of the basic
sum insured. Friends, the benefit
is bariatric surgery, which is
a unique feature of this policy. The benefit on bariatric surgery, that is,
surgery done for weight loss, will be
available only if it is recommended by at least 2
surgeons.
Some conditions are given along with it, which
can be seen in the policy document. Friends, these are the
benefits. Before taking the policy, it is
important to know the waiting period of the policy and also the
exclusions. Friends, whenever you
take a new policy, you will have to
wait for a minimum period to make a claim
and in the first 30 days, you can make only
accident related claim.
Friends, along with this, there is a list of some conditions
for which you will have to make a minimum period.  This will have to be done for a Twenty20 match.
Some examples of this are cataract,
entry related surgery, hernia, stone
related operation, joint
replacement etc. For the complete list, you
can refer to the policy document. Friends, the
waiting period for a pre-existing disease is
36 months. But there is an option
that if you pay an extra premium, you
can reduce the waiting period for your pre-existing disease, including total mastitis.
Now let's talk about some questions. This
health insurance policy does
not cover congenital gynecological birth defects.
Sexually transmitted diseases in the partner or
any disease caused by alcohol or drug abuse are
not covered. You
can refer to the policy document for the entire list.
Friends, if your age is more than 60 years, then
you will have to pay 10 percent
for every claim. But if your age is less than 60 years, then
no payment will be made.
Friends, let's move ahead and
understand with an example.
Suppose the premium is Rs.  Age is Atithi. He is
a healthy adult male. His annual
premium for the phablet policy will be
Rs 1000. There is no tax involved here.
Also, if Ram
also takes it for his parents whose age is
less than 35, then the total combined premium will be Rs
90. Withdrawal taxes. Friends,
if Ram takes the same policy for 45 years, then the
premium for his individual insurance will be Rs 33020. So you
can see that as this increases, the
premium amount also increases.
Friends, this premium depends on
your health condition. You can check your premium yourself as per your and
your family's health condition
on the Star Health Insurance website. If you
want, you
can take the policy online or
you
can take a decision as per your convenience through offline mode. Friends, here I would
like to tell you that Star Health
Insurance also covers all the coronavirus related
alarms. Friends, along with this,
I have made a video.  And I have made a video in which
I have compared Star Comprehensive
vs Star Family Health Optima vs
Star Medical Asif, you can also watch that,
friends, I hope you liked this video,
please like this video
and share it with your friends and family
and if you have any question
then definitely put it in the comment section of this video
and before leaving, do
not forget to subscribe to our channel Fan H, thank you and
stay healthy.